

DATA SCIENTIST · FULL STACK DEVELOPER · MASTERS STUDENT

Windsor, ON, Canada

🛘 (+1) 647-676-2057 | 🔀 niimshverma@ymail.com | 😭 nimishverma.codes | 🖸 bigpythonimish | 🖹 nimishcodes | 🗖 nimishcodes | 📂 My Scholar

Summary _____

Currently studying Masters in Science specialized in Computer Science from University of Windsor, expected to graduate in Winter 2020. Working on my thesis in Optimization using Evolutionary Algorithms. Super nerd who loves solving problems and coding in Python. Interested in formulating problem-solving method for big scale real life problems, and learning new technologies.

Education

University of Windsor, ON, Canada

92.67%

M.Sc. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

Sep. 2019 - Dec. 2020

- Fall 2019 Courses: Machine Learning and Pattern Recognition, Introduction to AI, and Privacy and Security on the Internet
- Winter 2020 Courses: Social Network Analysis, and Applications in Applied Al
- Graduate Teaching Assistant for Artificial Intelligence Concepts (F2019), and Advanced Topics in AI(W2020)

Guru Gobind Singh Indraprastha University, Delhi, India

83 %

B.Tech. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

Sep. 2015 - Jun. 2019

- CGPA 83 % out of 100 %
- Thesis on "Multi-Objective Feature Selection using Grey Wolf Optimization" under Dr. Deepak Gupta and Dr. Ashish Sharma.
- ACM-ICPC 2-time representative in Team AdHoc.

Work Experience _____

Vakil Desk New Delhi, India

FULL STACK DEVELOPER INTERN

Jun. 2018 -Oct. 2018, Jan. 2019 - April 2019

- Developed web-app using Django on Backend and Bootstrap/JS in Frontend.
- Implemented data analytics on public data available on an Indian government website
- Developed various RESTful APIs for the application to enable cross-platform compatibility
- Integrated easy-to-use Payment Module, Push Notifications, and Robotic Process Automation Tasks

Naustone Trades Arlington, Texas

MACHINE LEARNING (REMOTE) INTERN

May 2018 - Jun. 2018

- · Analysed Time Series data and performed Trend Analysis on top currency pairs to generate signals on best-performing pairs.
- Developed an Dockerfiles to deliver packages remotely

Lahag Spirits and Hotels

New Delhi, India

Data Analyst Intern

Dec. 2017 - Jan. 2018

- Built ETL pipelines to store data connected from the chains of hotel
- Reporting and Visualizing the data to the team of business analyst

NewsX, ITV Network

Noida, India

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER INTERN

Jun. 2017 - July 2017

- Developed Facebook Chat bot for news delivery.
- Developed Facebook Chat bot for news delivery.

Research

Soundex Algorithm for Hindi Language Names

Springer,Singapore

Jan. 2020

Co-author

• Published in Lecture Notes in Electrical Engineering, vol 612. Springer, Singapore.

• Oral Presentation at ICDSSA 2019 at BVCOE, New Delhi.

FEBRUARY 5, 2020 NIMISH VERMA · RÉSUMÉ 1

BJMR, Delhi

CO-AUTHOR Jan. 2018

• Presented at 3rd International Conference on "Managing Business Enterprises: Issues and Challenges" in BULMIM Journal of Management and Research (BJMR).

Extracurricular Activity_

Team AdHoc India

ACM ICPC International Collegiate Programming Contest

Dec. 2017, Dec. 2018

- Credentials: baylor.edu
- Ranked 45th in 2nd round held in IIT Kharagpur
- Ranked 48th in the second round held in Hindustan University, Chennai

Leaders for Tomorrow MAIT, Delhi

HEAD OF SOCIAL MEDIA TEAM

July 2017-April 2018

- In charge of the social media handles of LFT MAIT Chapter
- · Conducted periodic debates and discussions on Facebook
- Managed a team of promoters and influencers